The ship of hope, Espoir.
希望の船 エスポワール
It sails in the sea of darkness
filled with despair.
絶望を内包しながら
漆黒の海を行く
Nearing the end of
Restricted Rock Paper Scissors,
限定ジャンケンの終局間近
a man named Funai whom Kaiji
had encountered, stepped out...
カイジとは因縁浅からぬ男
船井が出した
...and suggested that they
shuffle and redistribute the cards.
カードをシャッフルし
配り直す提案
That would completely
ruin Kaiji's strategy...
それはカイジが立てた最終戦略
...of winning by hoarding
both Rocks and Paper!
グーとパー ダブル買い占めによる
必勝策の破綻につながる
しかし…
俺たちも加わる
But...
We'll join in too.
カイジ 苦渋の決断
It was a
bitter decision for Kaiji.
随分 遅い参加表明やな
You sure took
your time in deciding.
で おどれらのカードは何枚や？
Well, how many cards
do you have?
Even though it would
destroy their strategy,
買い占めの戦略が
破綻したとはいえ
unless they joined this circle,
この最終局面の
戦いの場に加わらなければ
Proclamation
there is no way they can
survive this battle.
生き残りは絶望的
だが勝負の機会さえあれば
まだ望みはある
Thus, as long there's still a
chance to play, hope is not lost.
カイジはそのギリギリの
活路に賭けた
Kaiji is betting on that
narrow route to survival.
69枚
69 cards.
これも配り直し効果や
This is an advantage of reshuffling.
Those who have been hoarding
cards can be forced out...
機をうかがって潜んだタヌキを
カード公表っちゅう煙が
いぶり出してくれる
...like badgers
from their holes.
Now, the number of cards should
match in numbers of the display.
これで電光掲示板と
カードの枚数は合う
Or so everyone thought.
誰もがそう思った　しかし
But...
They don't tally.
合わへん
グー38枚 パー37枚
けどチョキが12枚…
38 Rocks, 37 Papers...
But only 12 Scissors.
We are short by three.
３枚 足りへん
じゃあ 何か？
What then?
Are you suggesting that someone
in this group is hiding cards?!
まだ数をごまかしてる奴が
いるってのか この中に？
No, I doubt it.
いや それはないやろ
Think about it.
考えてみ　仮に
申告したカードの枚数以上は
If we set the rules that
you can only play...
戦わへんちゅう取り決めが
俺らの間で決まっとったら
...with the exact number
of cards that you declared,
３枚余計にカードを持つ奴は
the guy with three extra cards
would be sabotaging himself.
自分の首を
絞めることになるやないか
恐らく向こうや
どういうつもりか知らんけど
It's probably one of them!
Whatever it is...
He's in that group,
holding on to Scissors.
あの中におるんや
チョキを抱えたＸがな
An unknown, X.
今はこのことは棚上げや
Let's put that aside for now.
要は そいつと
戦わんかったらええ
It'll be fine as long
we don't play against him.
ほな 始めようか
Ok, let's begin then.
There's still a winning chance.
まだだ　まだ勝機はある
As long as we check the other
cards that were redistributed,
配り直されたカードを
チェックすれば
we can find out which card has
the greatest winning probability!
何を出せば一番 勝率が高いかを
69枚という圧倒的な数の
カードを持つ
With our large number
of 69 cards,
we're the only ones
with that ability.
俺たちだけが知ることができる
例えばシャッフル前と同じ
For example, before the shuffle,
given the deck of 30 Rocks,
5 Scissors, and 34 Papers,
グー30 チョキ５
パー34であれば
there is an 80% probability
for the Rocks to win.
チョキを殺すグーで勝負にいけば
８割近い勝率
内訳さえ分かれば勝つカードを
割り出すことは可能である
As long as the quantity
of each card is known,
the winning card
can be predicted.
The question is in being
able check the cards...
問題は配り直された後
いかに早く
カードをチェックできるか
...in the shortest time possible.
Right, I'll deal them.
ほな 配り直すで
みんな 自分が差し出した
カードの枚数を指で示してくれや
Everyone, use your fingers to
indicate how many cards you had.
Once I finish dealing,
we'll begin playing again.
配り終わったら即 勝負再開や
まず俺が２枚 高田さんが５枚
First, two cards for me.
Takada had five cards.
You had three cards
and your neighbour had one.
そっちが３枚 隣が１枚
そこが１枚 そっちが２枚
One card over there
and two cards here.
そして最後
カイジさんたちが69枚
And finally...
Kaiji and gang had 69.
これで おしまい
With this...
We're done.
さあ 勝負再開や
Alright, let's restart the game!
Funai!
船井！
悪いけど後にしてくれや
Sorry about that
but let's settle it later.
I have to find opponents
before there are none left.
早う戦わんと
相手がおらんようになるからな
You!
貴様！
カイジさん 早くこれ集めないと
Kaiji! We have to
gather them quickly!
クソッ
Darn it!
Darn it! Darn it! Darn it!
クソッ クソッ クソッ！
Anyway, you don't belong to
the kind who would make it.
しょせん生き残れる人間ちゃうわ
お前ら
Restricted Rock Paper Scissors
is a brutal game,
この限定ジャンケンは
バカが朽ち腐れて
優れた奴のみが生き残れる
弱肉強食のゲーム
where only the strong survive by
driving out the weak and foolish.
弱者は単たるエサにすぎんのや
The weak are
nothing more than bait!
沈む者 浮かび上がる者
Those who sink
and those who float...
In the midst of the
cheering and screams...
歓喜と悲痛の叫びが交差する中
シャッフル直後
13人いた勝負者たちは
After the shuffling,
out of the thirteen players,
seven were weeded out
in only one minute.
瞬く間に７人へと淘汰された
わずか１分の出来事　だが
But it was a crucial minute
of their lives!
その最初の１分こそが命だった
Kaiji had an unfortunate
delay in starting!
カイジ 痛恨の出遅れ
グー32 チョキ３ パー34
32 Rocks, 3 Scissors
and 34 Papers.
A total of 69 cards,
no mistake about that.
合計69　間違いない　あとは…
And...
グー34 チョキ８
パー… 34！？
34 Rocks, 8 Scissors
and... 34 Papers?!
俺たちのパーも34
We have 34 Papers too.
パーが尽きたんだ
The Papers are accounted for.
Excluding three unknown
Scissors cards and our own cards,
Xが持ってるはずのチョキ３枚と
俺たちの手持ちのカードを除けば
今 このフロアにあるのは
the cards remaining
on this floor, are...
グー２枚とチョキ２枚
Two Rocks and two Scissors.
つまりグーで勝負にいけば
悪くても２勝２分け
In other words,
if we play using Rocks,
we can get two wins
and two draws.
Or four straight wins!
あるいは４連勝の目もある
If we can get rid of the Scissors
in our 1st and 2nd games,
１勝目 ２勝目でチョキを
完全に殺すことができれば
then what's left is to get rid
of the Rocks using Paper.
残ったグーをパーで殺せばいい
The four remaining cards
are with...
残った４枚は船井
あそこの２人 あのメガネ
...Funai, the two over there
and that four-eyed guy.
この４人に１枚ずつ
They have one card each.
連中同士で決着をつけられる前に
I must do this before everyone
finishes challenging each other.
行くしかない！
This is the last attempt!
これがラスト･トライ
Don't say that and
accept my challenge.
そない言わんと勝負しようや
で でも…
船井
B-But...
Funai.
嫌がってる奴を
無理に誘うことないだろ
You needn't force him if
he doesn't want to play, right?
何やと？
やるなら俺と勝負しないか
What did you say?
How about playing against me?
You must be joking!
冗談やろ
クソッ　うん？
Darn it!
やらないか 俺と
Want to play against me?
座り込んでたって らちは明かねえ
You won't get anywhere
by sitting around.
いつかは戦うしかない　そうだろ
You'll have to play sometime.
Isn't that right?
だったら俺と…
So, let's have a game.
Hey! Are you stupid,
four-eyes?
寝ぼけとんか メガネ
This guy was buying cards!
こいつはカード買い占めてるんや
He can predict what the
winning cards are with his deck!
手持ちのカードから何が勝てるか
計ることもできるんやで
To play against him
is as good as suicide!
そんな奴らと戦うのか
自殺行為やで
終わった
もう誰も勝負してくれない
It's over! No one will
accept our challenge...
クソッ…
カイジさん
Darn it!
Kaiji!
Doomed!
破綻
途切れた
Our last line of hope
has been severed!
生き残りのための最後の糸
もうどうしていいのか 俺には…
I don't know what
to do anymore!
完全に破綻
Completely doomed!
It was already over...
元々 買い占め戦略なんか
みんなに知られた時点で泥舟
...the minute the others knew
you were hoarding cards.
Naturally, you'd sink.
沈むんが当たり前や
あとは仲良し３人
内輪で醜く争えや
You can now duel among yourselves
for the remaining time.
What are you doing?!
You scum!
よさんか
離れろ
Stop fighting!
Back off!
Using despicable means
all this while! You scum!
汚ねえ手ばっか 使いやがって
てめえ てめえ！
よせ
これは正当防衛でっせ
Stop!
I was just defending myself.
Kaiji!
カイジさん
That's right!
Dirty tricks are all you know!
クソッ　汚ねえ手ばかり…
Fool!
ボケ！勝負に汚いもクソもあるか
There are no morals
when it comes to winning!
うざいやっちゃ
大体 後からノコノコ出てきて
Stupid fool!
To start with, you interfered
with other's pre-...
人のえ… 相手に
ちょっかい出すからや
I mean, their opponents!
あんなボケ ほっとこうや のう？
Leave this fool alone!
What was the word you
wanted to say just now?
何が 人の｢え｣なんだ
You almost let the wrong word
slip out, didn't you?
お前 今 こう口走りそうに
なったんじゃないのか
｢人の｣
What you were about
to say, was...
"You interfered with
other's prey."
｢獲物に手を出すな｣と
In other words, you were
confident of winning.
てことは お前には確証があるんだ
そいつとの勝負に
必ず勝つという確証が
You had full assurance
of victory over that guy.
You tried to set him up!
策を打ったな
Your card is Scissors, right?
あんた 手持ちのカードは
チョキだろ
そ そんなこと…
W-Well...
I have 34 Paper cards.
俺たちの手元には
パーが34枚ある
The display also
shows 34 Papers.
電光掲示板のパーも34枚
つまり今 このフロアでは
パーは１枚も動いていないんだ
So, there are no Papers
in circulation on this floor.
If Funai is
confident of winning,
もし船井が勝つ確証があるなら
then your card
has to be a Scissors.
あんたのカードは
必然的にチョキってことになる
さっき船井に
手持ちのカード１枚で勝負して
Did anyone with one remaining
card lose to Funai just now?
負けた奴いるか
俺だ
I did.
What did you play?
何を出した
チョキ
Scissors.
Is this a coincidence, Funai?
これが偶然か？船井
お前が戦った
あるいは戦おうとした相手は
Both opponents you played
or wanted to play against...
２人とも手持ちが残り１枚で
カードの種類はチョキ
...had Scissors
as their last card.
These conditions show
very clearly that...
ここまで条件がそろえば明らかだ
お前は配り直した時
...you set yourself up to win
while shuffling the cards!
こっそりと
自分の必勝パターンを作り上げた
What proof do you have?!
何を根拠に…
ペテン師　裏切り者が！
Con artist! Traitor!
でっち上げだ！
何ぞ証拠でもあるんかい
That's a lie!
Have you any proof?!
こんな許されるんでっか？
Is this allowed?!
こいつは俺が憎くて
ただ おとしめとるんや
He's trying to frame me
because he hates me!
He's just trying to
mess up the arena!
場を無意味に混乱させとるんや
ぬかすな！
ペテン師野郎がペラペラと
That's enough blabber
to cover up your fraud!
客観的に見りゃ お前が
クロだってことは明白なんだよ
Looking at it objectively,
you're obviously guilty!
ほんなら言うてみ その証拠を
In that case, prove it!
Show me the proof!
There are at least three
suspicious things that you did.
お前には疑わしい点が少なくとも
３つある
何？
What?
The first thing.
疑惑の１つ目
お前は全員のカードを集めると
After gathering everyone's cards,
you checked the quantity
of each type of card.
グー チョキ パー
それぞれの数を確認し始めた
一刻を争うっていう緊急事態に
あんなことする必要ないだろ
That was unnecessary,
considering our situation...
...of being pressed for time.
You only had to count the total
number of cards and deal them.
手持ちのカードの数を確認すれば
あとはそれを配るだけでいい
お前がわざわざカードの
種類ごとに数を確認したのは
You deliberately counted
each type of card...
自分だけの理由 都合があった
...for your own motives
and convienence.
それは刻印
That was to mark them.
自分の目当てのカードに
印をつけること
You put a mark on
the cards you wanted.
違うか 船井
アホな　考えすぎやで
Am I wrong, Funai?
That's crazy! You're
thinking too far into this.
あります　引っかいたような跡
印が
Here it is,
a scratch mark on the back.
傷が何や
T-That's just a scratch!
Of course they'd be a little
scratched after so many dealings!
いろんな奴が触ったんやから
傷の１つや２つ つくやろ
傷をつけた後は
適当に切ったフリをして
After marking the cards,
you pretended to shuffle them,
配る時に自分にはグー
目当ての相手にはチョキを
then dealt Rocks to yourself
and Scissors to your targets.
シャッフルしたのは俺だけやない
I wasn't the
only one who shuffled!
不正が入る余地はないやんけ
There's no way
I could have cheated!
あのシャッフルは俺たちを
煙に巻く目くらまし
The shuffling was merely
a diversion tactic.
お前は自分以外の人間に
カードを切らせることによって
By using the shuffle
to divert our attention...
偽りの公正感 安心感を
演出しただけだ
...and making someone else
cut the deck,
you gave us a
false sense of fair play.
最後の最後にカードを
まとめるのも配るのも
As long as the redistribution
at the end was done by you,
お前である以上 途中で誰が
何回切ろうと一切関係ない
it doesn't mattter
who cut the deck!
The second thing.
疑惑の２つ目 最後のシャッフル
The last shuffle.
なぜカードを床に置いて
手で混ぜるようなマネをした
Why did you put the cards
on the floor to mix them?
そ そのほうが
誰が見ても公正やし
S-So that everyone
could see that it was fair,
カードも よう混ざる
違うな
and to mix it better...
Wrong.
お前はカードを
混ぜるフリをしながら
You pretended to mix them,
目印のついたカードを選んでいた
but were actually picking out
the cards you had marked.
お前にかかったら
どんな所作も悪だくみやないかい
You're just picking
on my every move!
じゃあ 聞こう
なぜ順不同だったんだ
In that case, let me ask.
Why were they
distributed at random?
疑惑の３つ目だ
お前はシャッフル後
The third thing.
After shuffling, you put two
cards in front of yourself first,
まず自分の前に
２枚のカードを置き
その後 右回りでも
左回りでもなく
then instead of going
clockwise or anti-clockwise,
バラバラと順不同に
カードを配った
you gave out the cards
in random order.
あんな配り方をする理由は１つ
There's only one reason
for distributing it that way.
目印のついたチョキを目当ての男
The reason was to give
the marked Scissors cards...
手持ちカード１枚の相手に
振り当てるため
...to your targets
who had only one card!
こんな たわ言
信じたらアカンで
Don't believe this nonsense!
こいつは買い占めを
思いつくような詐欺師や
He's the real swindler
who tried to hoard the cards!
船井 俺が詐欺師だろうと
人殺しだろうと事実は事実
Funai, it doesn't matter if
I'm a swindler or a murderer.
But facts don't change.
黙れ！なあ？
Shut up!
船井 てめえ… なめんなよ
Funai, you scum.
Don't take us for fools!
た 高田… 誤解や
クソッ！ふざけやがって
T-Takada, it's a misunderstanding!
Darn it. How dare you?!
こんなん全部 憶測の…
That was mere speculation!
Traitor!
裏切り者！
こうなっては 誰も船井とは戦わず
その戦略は水泡に帰す
From then on, everyone
refused to play against Funai.
His strategy had gone to waste.
It was ruin, brought about
by underestimating Kaiji!
カイジを甘く見すぎたための破綻
Funai is completely isolated.
船井 完全に孤立
かろうじて
一矢を報いたカイジだが
Although Kaiji had his revenge,
状況が好転したわけではない
his own situation did not
change for the better.
１秒ごとに狭められていく
With every second closing in,
カイジたちの可能性
存在する権利
Kaiji and his gang's possibilities
for a chance at survival...
同時に押し寄せてくる
...draw narrower.
自分の周りが縮小
息苦しい密室になる
In their hallucinating states,
their surroundings shrink
to become a suffocating space.
そんな幻想　結局 行き止まり
The situation was a dead end,
デッド ｢死｣という漆黒が
that led to a darkness
called death.
連中 なぜ戦わないんだ
Why aren't they playing?
そういえば確かに…
そうか！
Yeah, come to think of it...
I see!
あいつら戦わないんじゃない
戦えないんだ
They're not playing, not
because they don't want to.
It's because they can't!
パーのカードが
Once I announced that all the
Paper cards are in our possession,
すべて俺たちの手元にあると
公言された瞬間
運否天賦の幻想が消し飛んだ
the illusion of
fair play was lost.
What?
Excluding our cards,
俺たちのカード以外で
動いているのはグーとチョキだけ
the only cards in circulation
are Rocks and Scissors.
チョキ１枚の奴が
勝負にいくわけないだろ
A guy with only Scissors
can't possibly play, right?
奴らは星２つ　今 地獄と
天国のギリギリのラインにいる
Those guys have two stars each.
Right now, they're at the fine
border between heaven and hell.
だから動けないんだ
チョキが動かなきゃ
That's why they
can't make a move.
If Scissors is stuck,
Rocks can't be played either...
グーも動けない
出口のない袋小路
It's a looped situation.
いや これが突破口かもしれねえ
No, there might
still be a way out...
諦めるな　考えろ
Don't give up! Think!
何かあるはずだ
生き残る確率を増やす何か
There must be something!
There must be something
for the purpose of survival!
俺たちが生き残るには
In order for us to survive,
we must either win three games...
今 ホール内でカードを持つ
船井以外の３人に３勝する
...with the three remaining guys
besides Funai,
もしくは星を多く持つ船井と
or place a large bet for
three stars with Funai,
一気に星３つをかける
大勝負を仕掛け
who possesses
a number of stars.
これに勝って
星９個にたどり着くしかない
In winning that way,
we may get nine stars in total.
でも その両方ができないから
俺たち 苦労してんじゃないですか
But isn't the reason
for our sufffering now...
...because we
can't even do that?
連中に
勝負する気にさせる方法はある
There is a way to
make them want to play.
難しいのは もっと別の問題
The problem lies elsewhere.
偶数 奇数 また偶数か
Even, odd, even...
And there's the unknown, X.
それにＸもいる
どう考えても厳しい
It's complicated
no matter how I look at it.
Wait!
待てよ
カイジさん？
Kaiji?
カイジさん
- Kaiji?
- I found it!
見つかったぞ　究極の抜け道
The ultimate escape route...
必勝法
The winning strategy!
ただ まさに背水の陣
But it's definitely
the last resort.
仮にうまくいっても １度は
地獄をくぐってこなきゃならない
Even if all goes well,
we'll have to go
through hell once.
できることなら
こんな ばくちは打ちたくねえが
If possible, I'd choose to
avoid such a gamble.
仕方ない
もう時間切れ ギリギリ
But we haven't a choice.
Time is running out.
ぜいたくは言えない
We can't be too selective.
みんな聞け　俺に提案がある
Listen, everyone!
I have a suggestion!
このままじゃ時間だけが経過し
At this rate,
time will only run out...
最終的に全員
星２つのままが関の山だ
...and everyone will be left
with two stars at best.
道は１つ　俺と勝負しよう
There is only one way.
That is to play against me!
だけど お前らはカードを
大量に持っているじゃないか
But you guys have such a
large number of cards!
お前はカードを選べるが
俺たちは１枚
You have so much variety,
but we have only one card
and no other choice!
選択権はないんだぞ
だから
That is why I am
forfeiting that freedom.
その選択の権利を捨てよう
この３枚のカードを
シャッフルして
I'll shuffle these three cards
and line them up like this.
こうして並べる　それから先
Following which, you get
to choose which card I play.
俺のカードの選択を
お前たちに任せる
うまいこと言ったって
You make it sound ideal,
but don't you already know
what cards we have?
あんたは俺たちのカードが何かを
知ってるじゃないか
１枚ずつ別のカードを出すと
見せかけて
You can display a different card
while selecting them,
３枚とも僕のチョキを殺す
グーを並べるかもしれない
such as putting out
three Rocks to kill my Scissors.
いくら直前にシャッフルしても
ごまかすかもしれない
Even with shuffling,
it still might be a trap!
３枚とも見せよう
I will show you all three cards.
お前が１枚選び 勝負がついた後
You pick one card.
After the result, you may
check the other two cards.
残った２枚をめくって
確認してくれ
これなら不正やイカサマの
入る余地はない
This way, there will be
no means of cheating.
今は例え どんなに低い確率でも
This way, no matter
how small the possibility,
俺たちは３連勝　お前らは
最後の１枚を使っての１勝
the three of us have
a chance of victory.
And you have a chance to win
and get rid of your last card.
これに はるしかねえ
It's the only way!
今 戦わずに どんな勝算がある
What chance is there
if you don't fight now?
仮に俺があの船井と他の２人と
勝負して３連勝したら
If I beat Funai
and the other two,
もうお前とは戦わない
そうなれば
I'd have no need
to play against you.
And just like that, you'd lose
your chance at survival.
お前の生き残りの芽は
完全に消える
いいのか それで
Is that acceptable?
そうさ 俺たちは
進むしかねえんだ
That's right!
We have to move forward!
留まることは死だ
To stop would mean death!
セット　活路は前
Set!
The way to win, is forward!
オープン
Open!
や やったー！
We... We did it!
悪く思うなよ
Don't take it personally.
次 高田　来いよ
Next, Takada! Come on!
ちゅうちょしたって
時間が経つだけだ
By hesitating,
you're just wasting time!
Check!
チェック
この２人には分からない
なぜカイジが勝てるのか
The two of them
don't know how Kaiji won.
Set!
だが カイジが
必勝法と明言した以上
But since Kaiji declared
a winning strategy,
自分たちには気づかない
トリックが隠されている
they believed there had to
be a hidden trick somewhere.
そう思っていた
Open!
オープン
これで２勝目
This is the second win!
やったー！生き残った
次
Alright! I survived!
Next!
よし
カ カイジさん
Okay.
K-Kaiji!
いいんだ　ここまでは予定どおり
It's alright.
Everything is going as planned.
According to plan?
予定どおり？
オープン
やったー！
Open!
Alright!
やった やったー！
次
Alright! I did it!
Next!
Huh?
I get it!
そうか　今までの３人の
勝ち負けはどうでもよかったんだ
It didn't matter who won
or lost in these three matches!
狙いはただ１人　あの船井に
大勝負を仕掛けるために
The only aim was to set up
a large gamble with Funai.
来い 船井　決着をつけよう
Come on, Funai!
Let's settle this.
俺とお前の腐れ縁
決着？
Our inevitable showdown.
Settle?
ああ　これまで煮え湯を
飲まされ続けたそのツケを
Yeah.
I'll make you pay back for
each time you betrayed me.
一挙に払ってもらう
Five minutes more to go.
残り５分　限界まで行こう
俺たち３人の合計
Let's go for broke.
The total sum of five stars
from the three of us!
星５つの大勝負
何！？
What?!
限定ジャンケン　その最終局面
It is the final match of
Restricted Rock Paper Scissors.
地獄へのタイムリミットまで
あとわずか
The time limit to hell
is just round the corner!
次回 ｢鉄槌｣
Next, Iron Hammer.